Murat Ogulcan Sahin

Brooklyn, NY | 619-519-8864 | muratogulcansahin@gmail.com Website | GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based web development. Coming from a background in statistics and mathematics which helped me to develop problem solving, analytical and critical thinking skills. Equipped with a strong understanding of software architecture, design patterns and object-oriented programming. Always passionate to improve my software engineering skill set.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript programming bootcamp

01/2021 - 06/2021

Istanbul University Istanbul, Turkey Maritime Transportation and Management Engineering (BS)

Related Studies: Statistics, Mathematics, MATLAB

07/2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, SQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, Three.js, Git, GitHub, HTML, CSS, REST, AJAX

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Space Cruise - GitHub | Demo | Walkthrough

A space travel service that allows users to book trips to planets on a 3D platform.

- Developed JavaScript/React/Redux front-end and Ruby/Rails/SQLite3 back-end
- Implemented 'redux-thunk' middleware enhancer to dispatch asynchronous functions
- Exploited Three.js React extension to create 3D user experience.

Dance Memory - GitHub | Demo | Walkthrough

A SPA memory card game with fun dancing stickers.

- Utilized CRUD actions with adhering RESTful API architecture
- Employed vanilla JS to handle DOM events with AJAX techniques
- Devised API responses with serializers that use Active Record Interface Query methods to boost query performance

Icy Truck - GitHub | Demo | Walkthrough

A Rails app where users can purchase or sell ice cream from their own ice cream truck.

- Programmed with Ruby on Rails in backend and frontend
- Authenticated users with Facebook accounts using 'omniauth'
- Encrypted and secured user password via 'bcrypt' hashing
- Generated nested forms and models to reduce fetch requests for better user experience

EXPERIENCE

Uber / Lyft New York, NY

Ride Share Driver (over 15,000 rides and a service rating of 4.99 out of 5)

12/2016 - Present

- Provide expert ride share service to clients as an independent contractor for Uber/Lyft
- Manage my own hours and averaged about 60 hours a week in a client facing role
- Create an efficient schedule for work times that maximized my weekly earnings
- Decrease yearly maintenance and repair expenses by building strong networks with service providers

YASA Tanker Istanbul, Turkey **Voyage Operation and Chartering Intern** 05/2014 - 07/2015

- Ordered mechanical parts for the fleet to increase net profit margin
- Investigated charter parties to prevent decrease in company's year-end financial performance